<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode  type="Source" icon="db_redshift_connector.png"
xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.6" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.6 http://knime.org/node/v3.6.xsd">
    <name>Amazon Redshift Connector</name>
    <shortDescription>Create a database connection to Amazon Redshift.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
            This node creates a connection to Amazon Redshift using the native Amazon Redshift JDBC driver. You need to provide the server's
            hostname (or IP address), the port, and a database name. Login credentials can either be provided directly in
            the configuration or via credentials set on the workflow.
            </p>
            <p>
            For more information visit <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/redshift/">Amazon Redshift</a> and also the 
            <a href="https://forums.aws.amazon.com/forum.jspa?forumID=155&amp;start=0">AWS Forums</a>.
            </p>
            <p>
            This node uses the selected driver's 
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/db_extension_guide/index.html#url_template">JDBC URL template</a> 
            to create the concrete database URL. Field validation in the dialog depends on whether the (included) 
            tokens referencing them are mandatory or optional in the template.
            </p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Connection settings">
            <option name="Database Dialect">
                Choose the registered database dialect here.
            </option>
            <option name="Driver Name">
                Choose the registered database driver here. Additional drivers can be registered via KNIME's preference 
                page "KNIME -> Databases". For more details on how to register a new driver see the
                <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/db_extension_guide/index.html#register_jdbc">database documentation</a>.
            </option>
            <option name="Hostname">
                The hostname (or IP address) of an Amazon Redshift server. The corresponding driver URL template
                variable is <tt>host</tt>.
            </option>
            <option name="Port">
                The port on which the Amazon Redshift server is listening. The default port
                is 5,439. The corresponding driver URL template variable is <tt>port</tt>.
            </option>
            <option name="Database name">
                The name of the database you want to connect to. The corresponding driver URL template variable is
                <tt>database</tt>.
            </option>
            <option name="Credentials">
                If checked, the credentials (user and password) are used as defined on
                the workflow. The credential name links to the specified user and password.
            </option>
            <option name="Username &amp; password">
                Your log-in user name and password for the database. Note that the password 
                is encrypted before storage and decrypted afterwards for being used internally.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="JDBC Parameters">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define JDBC driver connection parameter. The value of a parameter can be a 
                constant, variable, credential user, credential password or KNIME URL.
                For more information about the supported driver properties see the 
                <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/redshift/latest/mgmt/configure-jdbc-options.html">Redshift documentation</a>.
             </description>
             <option name=""></option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define KNIME framework properties such as connection handling,
                advanced SQL dialect settings or logging options.
            </description>
            <option name=""></option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Input Type Mapping">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define rules to map from database types to KNIME types.
            </description>
            <option name="Mapping by Name">
                Columns that match the given name (or regular expression) and database type will be mapped
                to the specified KNIME type.
            </option>
            <option name="Mapping by Type">
                Columns that match the given database type will be mapped to the specified KNIME type.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Output Type Mapping">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define rules to map from KNIME types to database types.
            </description>
            <option name="Mapping by Name">
                Columns that match the given name (or regular expression) and KNIME type will be mapped
                to the specified database type.
            </option>
            <option name="Mapping by Type">
                Columns that match the given KNIME type will be mapped to the specified database type.
            </option>
        </tab>   
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Amazon Redshift Connection">Amazon Redshift connection</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
