<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./redshift-launcher-icon.png" type="Source" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Amazon Redshift Cluster Launcher</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
    	Creates an Amazon Redshift Cluster.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	<p>
        		This node creates an Amazon Redshift Cluster according to the settings provided. 
        		The clusters information, such as hostname, port and default database name, are provided as flow variables.
        		<br/>
        		<br/>
        		Creating an Amazon Redshift Cluster can take several minutes to complete, 
        		during this time the node will remain in the executing state.
        	</p>
        	<p>
        		For further documentation please take a look at the <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/documentation/redshift/">Redshift Documentation</a>.
        	</p>
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Authentication">
        Method for authentication
        	<br/>
        	<b>Workflow Credentials</b>
        	<br/>
        	Use workflow credentials to determine the access key ID and the secret access key. 
        	The login is used as the access key ID and the password is used as the secret access key.
        	<br/>
        	<b>Access Key ID and Secret Access Key</b>
        	<br/>
        	The AWS access key ID used to authenticate.
        	<br/>
        	The AWS secret access key used to authenticate.
        	<br/>
        	<b>Default Credential Provider Chain</b>
        	<br/>
        	When selected the default credential provider chain is used for authentication. Default location is "~/.aws/credentials" on most platforms. 
       	</option>
        <option name="Region">
        	The Amazon AWS geographical region the cluster should be launched in.
        </option>
        <option name="Polling interval [s]">
        	The interval (in seconds) in which the cluster status should be checked during creation.
        </option>
        <option name="Cluster name">
        	The name for the cluster
        	<br/>
        	<b>Browse...</b>
        	<br/>
        	This allows to browse already existing clusters. Existing cluster names can then be selected from a list.
        </option>
        <option name="Port number">
        	The port number for the cluster
        </option>
        <option name="Redshift credentials">
        	Credentials to be used for the redshift cluster
        	<br/>
        	<b>Workflow Credentials</b>
        	<br/>
        	Use workflow credentials to determine the master user and the master password 
        	<br/>
        	<b>Username &amp; password</b>
        	<br/>
        	Determine the master user and the master password
        </option>
        <option name="Database name">
			The name for the default database
        </option>
        <option name="The node type">
			The node type used for the cluster
        </option>
        <option name="Number of nodes">
			The number of nodes in the cluster. Choosing 1 node creates a single-node cluster. Choosing 2 or more nodes create a multi-node cluster.
        </option>
        <option name="Fail if cluster exists">
			Whether the node should fail if a cluster with the given name already exists.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>        
        <outPort index="0" name="Redshift cluster flow variables">
        	Port serving all the necessary variables to access the redshift cluster
        </outPort>        
    </ports>        
</knimeNode>
