<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="../../s3/node/file_system_connector.png"
		type="Source"
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">

    <name>Amazon S3 Connector</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Provides a file system connection to Amazon S3.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	<p>
				This node configures the connection information that will be used to connect to Amazon S3. Using this 
        		connection the other KNIME remote file handling nodes such as Excel Reader and Excel Writer can  
        		download and upload files from and to Amazon S3. 
        	</p>
        	<p>
        		For further documentation please take a look at the <a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/gsg/GetStartedWithS3.html">AWS Documentation</a>.
        	</p>
        	<p><b>Path syntax:</b> Paths for Amazon S3 are specified with a UNIX-like syntax, /mybucket/myfolder/myfile. An absolute
            for S3 consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading slash ("/").</li>
                    <li>Followed by the name of a bucket ("mybucket" in the above example), followed by a slash.</li>
                    <li>Followed by the name of an object within the bucket ("myfolder/myfile" in the above example).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            
            <p><b>URI formats:</b> When you apply the <i>Path to URI</i> node to paths coming from this connector, you can create URIs with the following formats:
                <ol>
                    <li><b>Presigned https:// URLs</b> which contain credentials, that allow to access files for a certain amount of time
                    (see <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/userguide/ShareObjectPreSignedURL.html">AWS documentation</a>).</li>
                    <li><b>s3:// URLs</b> to access Amazon S3 with the <tt>aws</tt> command line interface, or inside Hadoop environments.</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Settings">
        	<option name="Working directory">
	            Specifies the <i>working directory</i> using the path syntax explained above. The working directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream
	            nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i> paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading slash. If not specified, the default working directory
	            is "/".
	        </option>
	        <option name="Normalize paths">
	            Determines if the path normalization should be applied. Path normalization eliminates redundant components of a path like, e.g. /a/../b/./c" can be normalized to "/b/c".
	            When these redundant components like "../" or "." are part of an existing object, then normalization must be deactivated in order to access them properly.
	        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
        	<option name="Read/write timeout in seconds">The socket read/write timeout. For further details see the 
            	<a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSJavaSDK/latest/javadoc/com/amazonaws/ClientConfiguration.html#setSocketTimeout-int-">S3 documentation</a>.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Server-side encryption (SSE)">If selected, all data written to S3 will be encrypted with 
        		<a href ="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/serv-side-encryption.html">Server-side encryption (SSE)</a>. All 3 modes are supported.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Use default AWS managed key">If SSE-KMS is selected as the SSE method, then this option specifies whether or not to
    	    	encrypt data with the default AWS managed CMK.
        	</option>
        	<option name="KMS key id">If SSE-KMS is selected as the SSE method and the default AWS managed CMK should <b>not</b> be used, then
        	this option allows to choose the KMS key with which to encrypt data written to S3. Click on <i>List keys</i> to fetch the list of available
        	keys (requires permissions <tt>kms:ListKeys</tt>, <tt>kms:DescribeKey</tt> and optionally <tt>kms:ListAliases</tt>).
        	</option>
        	<option name="Customer key">If SSE-C is selected as the SSE method it is necessary to provide an encryption key. There are multiple ways the key
        	could be provided. Base64 encoded key-string could be entered directly or provided via credentials variable. The third way is to select a key file
        	which has the key stored as plain bytes.
        	</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
	<ports>
	     <inPort index="0" name="Connection information port">
        	Port object containing the AWS connection information.
        </inPort>
        <dynInPort insert-before="0" name="File System Connection" group-identifier="File System Connection"> 
			A file system connection to read/write the customer key, when <b>SSE-C</b> encryption mode is enabled.
		</dynInPort>  
		<outPort index="0" name="S3 File System Connection">S3 File System Connection</outPort>
	</ports>        
</knimeNode>
