<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./redshift-deleter-icon.png" type="Source" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Amazon Redshift Cluster Deleter</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
    	Delete an Amazon Redshift Cluster according to the settings provided.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	<p>
        		This node deletes an Amazon Redshift Cluster according to the settings provided. 
        		<br/>
        		<br/>
        		You can find created snapshots in your <a href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/console">AWS management console for Redshift</a>.
        	</p>
        	<p>
        		For further documentation please take a look at the <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/documentation/redshift/">Redshift Documentation</a>.
        	</p>
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Authentication">
        Method for authentication
        	<br/>
        	<b>Workflow Credentials</b>
        	<br/>
        	Use workflow credentials to determine the access key ID and the secret access key. 
        	The login is used as the access key ID and the password is used as the secret access key.
        	<br/>
        	<b>Access Key ID and Secret Access Key</b>
        	<br/>
        	The AWS access key ID used to authenticate.
        	<br/>
        	The AWS secret access key used to authenticate.
        	<br/>
        	<b>Default Credential Provider Chain</b>
        	<br/>
        	When selected the default credential provider chain is used for authentication. Default location is "~/.aws/credentials" on most platforms. 
       	</option>
        <option name="Region">
        	The Amazon AWS geographical region the cluster should be deleted in.
        </option>
        <option name="Polling interval [s]">
        	The interval (in seconds) in which the cluster status should be checked after issuing the delete order.
        </option>
        <option name="Cluster name">
        	The name of the cluster
        	<br/>
        	<b>Browse...</b>
        	<br/>
        	This allows to browse existing clusters. Existing cluster names can then be selected from a list.
        </option>
        <option name="Final snapshot name">
			The name of the final snapshot that can be created when deleting a Redshift cluster.
        </option>
        <option name="Skip final snapshot">
			Whether the creation of the final snapshot should be skipped.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>      
    <inPort index="0" name="Flow Variables">Optional input containing flow variables for parameterization.</inPort>
    </ports>  
</knimeNode>
