<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Other"
	icon="amazon_personalize_upload_item_data.png">
	<name>Amazon Personalize Upload Items</name>
	<shortDescription>Uploads items data to the Amazon Personalize space.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node uploads items data to the Amazon Personalize space. The
			input table must contain at least one string column that contains
			item IDs and one additional metadata column (string or numeric).
			First, this node uploads the data to a specified S3 location. From
			there, it will be imported to Personalize. The import may take
			several minutes. If the import is done, the file will be
			deleted
			from
			S3 afterwards since it is not needed anymore.
			<br />
			To
			create a model with Amazon Personalize, you can also upload
			users
			and
			interactions data to the same data group. Only the interactions
			data is
			required. Once you have
			uploaded
			all the data, you can
			create a
			solution
			with the
			<i>Amazon Personalize Create Solution Version</i>
			node and afterwards deploy the solution by creating a campaign with
			the
			<i>Amazon Personalize Create Campaign</i>
			node.
			<br />
			More
			information is available on the
			<a href="https://aws.amazon.com/personalize/">website</a>
			or in the
			<a
				href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/personalize/latest/dg/personalize-dg.pdf">documentation</a>
			.
			<br />
			<br />
			<i>Note:
				If
				the
				node execution is interrupted
				during
				the
				import, e.g. by
				the user or due to lost of internet connection, the import
				will
				still
				be
				completed
				on
				AWS,
				although the node does not execute
				successfully. The
				file on S3 may not be deleted in this case.
			</i>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Target on S3">Specify the location on S3 which will be used to
				store the
				dataset while it gets imported to Personalize. The file is
				just
				temporarily stored and will be deleted after the node has been
				executed. If the execution of the node is interrupted or the
				internet connection gets lost while importing is in progress, the
				file may not be deleted.
			</option>
			<option name="Enter custom IAM role ARN">
				Enter a custom AWS IAM role. The role must have
				access to the
				previously defined S3 bucket. See also
				<a
					href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/personalize/latest/dg/API_CreateDatasetImportJob.html">here</a>
				.
			</option>
			<option name="Select IAM role ARN">
				Select one of the available AWS IAM role. The
				role must have
				access to
				the previously defined S3 bucket. See also
				<a
					href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/personalize/latest/dg/API_CreateDatasetImportJob.html">here</a>
				.
			</option>
			<option name="Upload to new dataset group">Enter a custom AWS IAM role. The role must have
				access to the previously defined S3 bucket.
			</option>
			<option name="Upload to existing dataset group">Select one of the available AWS IAM role. The
				role must have
				access to the previously defined S3 bucket.
			</option>
			<option name="Item ID column">Select the column that contains item IDs.
			</option>
			<option name="Metadata columns">Select at least one and up to 5 metadata columns.
			</option>
			<option name="Dataset name">Specify the dataset name.</option>
			<option name="Prefix of import job name">Specify a prefix for the name of the import job.
				The full name will consist of this prefix and a timestamp.
			</option>
			<option name="Prefix of schema name">Specify a prefix for the name of the schema. The
				full name will consist of this prefix and information about the
				metadata types.
			</option>
			<option name="If a items dataset already exists...">
				Select the policy to apply if the selected dataset group already
				contains a items dataset. If
				<i>Overwrite</i>
				is selected, the existing dataset will be deleted and a new one
				created. Otherwise, the node will fail.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort name="AWS connection information" index="0">The AWS
			connection information.
		</inPort>
		<inPort name="Input data" index="1">The input table
			containing the
			items data.
		</inPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
