<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode 
	icon="./s3filepicker16x16.png" type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>Amazon S3 File Picker (legacy)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Generates a pre-signed URL of an Amazon S3 object. 
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
	        This node reads the Amazon S3 connection and generates a pre-signed URL that points to an Amazon S3 object.
	        The URL is only valid for a specific period of time. Upon expiry, the URL will no longer remain active and an 
	        attempt to access the URL once it has expired will generate an error. It is not needed to set the permission
	        to access the S3 object to public. Using the generated pre-signed URL, any KNIME reader can be utilized to 
	        directly read the S3 object without having to fetch the object locally first.
		    <br/><br/>
		    URLs can be signed for a maximum of <b>7 days</b>.
        	<p>
        		<i>This is a legacy file handling node and has been replaced by the</i> <a href="https://kni.me/n/YMvcvDu5EC56OIFg">
        		<i>Path to URI</i></a> node.
        		<i>For further information about the new file handling framework see the </i>
        		<a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/analytics_platform_file_handling_guide/index.html"><i>File Handling Guide.
        		</i></a><br/>
			</p>
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Remote File">
        	The Amazon S3 object, from which the pre-signed URL should be created.
        </option>
        <option name="Expiration">
        Method of expiration
            <br/>
            <b>After Duration</b>
            <br/>
            The URL will expire after a certain duration from when the node is executed.
            <br />
            <b>On Date</b>
            <br />
            The URL will expire on a set date.
        </option>
               
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Connection Information Port">
        	Port object containing the connection information to Amazon S3.
        </inPort>        
        <outPort index="0" name="Pre-signed URL Variable">
        	Variable port object containing the pre-signed URL to an Amazon S3 object.
        </outPort>        
    </ports>        
</knimeNode>
