<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcDoc2String.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Amazon Comprehend (Key Phrases)</name>
	<shortDescription>Locates key phrases in text utilizing the Amazon Comprehend service.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node discovers key phrases within text by utilizing the Amazon Comprehend service. 
            Amazon Comprehend is a natural language processing (NLP) service that uses machine learning to discover insights from text.
            The Comprehend service returns the key phrases or talking points and a confidence score to support that this is a key phrase.
            A key phrase consists of a noun and 
            modifiers that distinguish the noun phrase (e.g. "a beautiful day").<br/>
            The new data table contains a new row for every discovered key phrase as well as a score column which indicates
            the level of confidence that the text is a key phrase. Additionally, there are columns that define the 
            start and end offsets of the key phrase within the input text. The offsets can be used to extract a key phrase
            from the original text<br/>
            <br/>
            For more information about AWS Comprehend can be found on <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/comprehend/features/">this website.</a>
        </intro>
 		<tab name="General options">
        <option name="Text column">
            The input column containing the text or documents to analyze for key phrases.
        </option>
        <option name="Source language">
            Select the language of the incoming text.
        </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
		<inPort name="AWS connection information" index="0">The AWS connection information.</inPort>
        <inPort name="Text input table" index="1">The input table
        containing the text on which to apply key phrase detection.</inPort>    
        <outPort name="Documents output table" index="0">An output table
        containing one key phrase per row, as well as a score and the key phrase's offsets within the input text.</outPort>
    </ports>  
</knimeNode>
