<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10" type="Source"
    icon="db_redshift_connector.png" deprecated="true">
    <name>Amazon Redshift Connector</name>
    <shortDescription>Create a database connection to Amazon Redshift.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
            This node is part of the deprecated database framework.
            For more information on how to migrate to the new database framework see the
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/db_extension_guide/index.html#migration">migration section</a> of the 
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/db_extension_guide/index.html">database documentation</a>.
            </p>
            <p>
            This node creates a connection to Amazon Redshift using the native Amazon Redshift JDBC driver. You need to provide the server's
            hostname (or IP address), the port, and a database name. Login credentials can either be provided directly in
            the configuration or via credentials set on the workflow.
            </p>
            <p>
            For more information visit <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/redshift/">Amazon Redshift</a> and also the <a href="https://forums.aws.amazon.com/forum.jspa?forumID=155&amp;start=0">AWS Forums</a>.
            </p>
            
        </intro>

        <option name="Hostname">
            The hostname (or IP address) of the Amazon Redshift endpoint.
        </option>
        <option name="Port">
            The port on which amazon Redshift is listening. The default port is 5439.
        </option>
        <option name="Database name">
            The name of the database you want to connect to.
        </option>
        <option name="Parameter">
            Optional connection parameter such as ssl or authentication options.
            <br />
            For Amazon Redshift specific settings see <a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/redshift/latest/mgmt/configure-jdbc-options.html">JDBC Driver Configuration Options</a>
        </option>
        <option name="SSL">Connect using ssl</option>
        <option name="Use credentials">
            Selection this option if you want to provide authentication data via workflow credentials.
            Then select the desired credential name in the list below.
        </option>
        <option name="Use username &amp; password">
            Provide a username and a password for authentication. The password may be optional if the
            server is configured accordingly.
        </option>
        <option name="Timezone correction">
            Select the TimeZone to convert the date, time or timestamp field into. The current implementation can't
            represent time zones. In order to support persisting those fields into a database, the time values can be
            changed according to the selected time zone, which is used as the offset (including the daylight saving
            time)
            for the original values:

            <ul>
                <li>
                    <i>No correction (use UTC)</i>
                    is used for workflows (created before 2.8) and doesn't apply any correction,
                </li>
                <li>
                    <i>Use local timezone</i>
                    uses the local time zone offset to correct the date field before reading or writing, and
                </li>
                <li>
                    <i>Use selected timezone</i>
                    allows selecting the time zone to covert the date values into.
                </li>
            </ul>
        </option>
        <option name="Allow spaces in column names">
            Check this option if the database can handle spaces in column names. Otherwise KNIME will replace them by
            underscores.
        </option>
        <option name="Validate connection on close">
            Check this option if you want to validate the connection when closing the dialog.
        </option>
        <option name="Retrieve metadata in configure">
            This option controls subsequent nodes. Usually when a database node is configured it retrieves the metadata of the
            current table or query from the database for usage in subsequent nodes. If metadata retrieval takes quite
            some time it will slow down workflow configuration and execution noticeably, especially since metadata is
            retrieved in both configure and execute. In such cases it's better to switch this option off and
            only retrieve metadata during execute.
        </option>        
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Database JDBC Connection">A database JDBC connection</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
